Qiaoyi Liu (Joyce)

Full-stack Software Engineer

t: 650-772-2987 e: qyliu10@gmail.com Cupertino, CA 95014 <u>Linkedin</u> <u>GitHub</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

Skills

Python, Javascript, React, Redux, Node.js, Flask, Express, Restful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, SQLAlchemy, AWS, HTML, CSS, Pug, Github, Git, Docker, Heroku, Playwright

Projects

Klickr - an image-sharing and social networking platform inspired by Flickr.

live github

(Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, AWS, HTML, CSS, Docker, Heroku)

- Worked independently on creating 4 backend API routes, leveraging 18 react components, and utilizing vanilla css to build a responsive and dynamic web page.
- Used React frontend with Flask backend to update the PostgreSQL database and Redux store for instant creating, adding, updating, removing albums, images, comments and likes.
- Created custom modal using React component architecture allowing for efficient development of new forms.
- Utilized AWS S3 to implement user image uploads reducing server load and improving user experience.

NotesOn - a notes-taking app, inspired by Evernote, where users can organize notes in a simple way. <u>live | github</u> (Express, React, Redux, JavaScript, Sequelize, Node JS, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Heroku)

- Worked independently on developing 3 API routes and various frontend react components for a logged-in user to create, read, edit, delete and search for their notes and notebooks.
- Configured Node backend with PostgreSQL, using Sequelize ORM for validations and database queries.
- Integrated react-quill library to create rich-text editor where users can edit and format notes easily.
- Implemented custom searching to facilitate notes searches throughout the site.

Wecord - a discord clone app, which allows users to hang out with friends and communities.

(Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Docker, WebSocket, Heroku)

- Collaborated with 3 other engineers to develop a full-stack application with 5 core features within a week.
- Designed and built a backend database and 6 RESTful API routes by utilizing Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy.
- Combined SocketIO to implement live chat functions for better user experience.

Experience

Web Developer | Freelance | 2023 - present

- ImageStudio a MERN stack project allowing users to share thoughts and locations in real-time.
- iChat an ongoing cloud-based messaging application project that users can connect anytime and anywhere.

Business Analyst | Vivolight Technology | 2018 - 2020

• Conducted in-depth overseas marketing analysis and carried out effective solutions to boost organizational efficiencies, resulting in a 30% increase in user satisfaction..

Business Consultant | Chong Sheng Consultants | 2016 - 2018

• Supported corporate project management of large scale human resource solutions through cross-functional business collaboration.

Account manager | China Industrial Bank | 2015 - 2016

• Performed in-depth credit analysis of corporate clients, assessed credit risks and issued risk opinions on a regular basis for senior management decisions.

Education

App Academy | Full Stack Web Development Training, US

Immersive software development course with over 1000 hours of class work focusing on full stack web development. **University of Sheffield** | Master of Science | Sheffield, United Kingdom

Major in International Business and obtained Sheffield Graduate Award in 2015.